<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Spark on Chen Zhe&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://chen-zhe.github.io/blog/categories/spark/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Spark on Chen Zhe&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 05 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://chen-zhe.github.io/blog/categories/spark/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Manuscript: Cell Sector Clustering</title>
      <link>https://chen-zhe.github.io/blog/p/manuscript-cell-sector-clustering/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chen-zhe.github.io/blog/p/manuscript-cell-sector-clustering/</guid>
      <description>Presentation video at IEEE WCNC 2020
When I was with DataSpark, I was part of a product team building a telco-specific solution that optimizes a telco operator&amp;rsquo;s spending on cell site upgrades to maximize return on investment (ROI). Requested by one of our clients, I designed, implemented and deployed this algorithm to identify cell sector clusters that share user load. Discovery of the sharing capability reduces the need to upgrade cell sites and hence saves upgrade cost.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Basic usage of GraphX for clique detection</title>
      <link>https://chen-zhe.github.io/blog/p/basic-usage-of-graphx-for-clique-detection/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chen-zhe.github.io/blog/p/basic-usage-of-graphx-for-clique-detection/</guid>
      <description>GraphX is a powerful component in Spark that allows graph-based programming and manipulation at very large scale. The only drawback is that it run on RDD and not DataFrame as I&amp;rsquo;m used to in Spark 2.2. Although a Spark package called GraphFrames is available to extend GraphX&amp;rsquo;s power to DataFrame, I recon it&amp;rsquo;s still easier to learn to construct a graph using GraphX and RDD than importing the package in Spark.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apache Spark - Save Time with Less Join Operations</title>
      <link>https://chen-zhe.github.io/blog/p/apache-spark-save-time-with-less-join-operations/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chen-zhe.github.io/blog/p/apache-spark-save-time-with-less-join-operations/</guid>
      <description>Not long ago, I was tasked to improve our Spark application&amp;rsquo;s runtime performance as some modules takes 7 hours or more to complete on datasets that are not considered very large. This is my conclusion and afterthoughts after countless hours staring at our codebase and YARN application tracking UI. I was able to achieve 30% ~ 80% reduction of runtime, depending on how well the module was written and the nature of operations.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
