<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Notes on 大白鲸笔记本</title>
    <link>https://chen-zhe.github.io/blog/categories/notes/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Notes on 大白鲸笔记本</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 23 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://chen-zhe.github.io/blog/categories/notes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How to be a better software engineer</title>
      <link>https://chen-zhe.github.io/blog/p/how-to-be-a-better-software-engineer/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chen-zhe.github.io/blog/p/how-to-be-a-better-software-engineer/</guid>
      <description>After graduation from my Master&amp;rsquo;s, I decided to get some advice from my advising professors before I embark (again) on a journey to be a better software engineer. Here are his advice that I feel are words to remember:
Know the full stack, not just how to build applications
The article I will refer to later had a few perfect examples: a bug in web indexing was ultimately traced to faulty hardware.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to get hired as a software engineer? A note to myself after 3 interviews as an interviewer</title>
      <link>https://chen-zhe.github.io/blog/p/how-to-get-hired-as-a-software-engineer-a-note-to-myself-after-3-interviews-as-an-interviewer/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chen-zhe.github.io/blog/p/how-to-get-hired-as-a-software-engineer-a-note-to-myself-after-3-interviews-as-an-interviewer/</guid>
      <description>TL;DR
To pose myself as a good software engineer candidate, I need to:
Demonstrate passion to learn Provide more utility to the job position as a senior engineer Keep my resume short and relevant Tailor my resume for each position that I apply to Be mentally prepared for a project with relevancy to the position I&amp;rsquo;m applying to Not forget about the basics of computing (data structure and algorithms) Demonstrate Passion for coding Background In the past few weeks, I participated in 3 interview sessions to hire more software engineers for developing the Spark ETL pipeline (using Scala) of a product.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
